《福尔摩斯历险记》
《硬纸盒案》
我并非说制服不适合你
Now I won't say as how the uniform don't suit you,
库欣小姐 但很高兴看到你没有穿着它来
Miss Cushing. But it is nice to see you out of it.
莎拉 莎拉
Sarah, Sarah.
您肯定是另一位库欣小姐
You must be the other Miss Cushing.
今天非常开心吧 对于你们三姐妹来说
Isn't this a happy day then, eh, for all three of you.
是的 是的 当然是
Yes, yes it is, of course it is.
来了
Just coming.
盗墓贼在伦敦北部大肆作案
"Body Snatchers Strike in North London."
我们在处理一桩现代版的伯克和黑尔案吗？
"Are we dealing with a modern version of Burke and Hare?"
不幸的是 在这个时节里解剖学院并不需要
Well, sadly, the anatomy schools don't need the help
盗墓贼的帮助
of body snatchers at this time of the year.
他们存了很多从救济院运来的尸体
They are well stocked with corpses from the poor.
那你怎么看呢？
What do you think then?
我不知道 也许是某种古怪的祭礼吧
I don't know. Some outlandish cult, perhaps.
他们就此事咨询过你了吗 福尔摩斯
Have you been consulted on the subject Holmes?
进来 霍金斯
Come in, Hawkins.
啊哈 霍金斯
Ah Hawkins.
请自便 来点咖啡吧
Make yourself at home. Have a cup of coffee.
谢谢
Thank you.
你把记录带来了吗
Have you brought those descriptions?
是的 带来了
Yes, yes I have.
现已被挖走的尸体有 艾伯特 考特 48岁
Bodies so far exhumed, "Albert Cotter, forty eight."
沙德韦尔的守鱼人 死于心脏病
"Fish porter of Shadwell. Heart disease."
马丁 鲁伯里 44岁 死于肝硬化
"Martin Rubery, fifty four. Cirrhosis of the liver."
对他不甚了解
We don't know much about him, except it was thought
只知道他年轻时曾是一名业余拳击手
he was an amateur pugilist of some sort in his youth.
杰米 金 39岁 女修道院花园看守人
"Jimmy King, thirty nine. Covent Garden Porter."
死于脑出血
"Cerebral hemorrhage."
你会继续追查吗
You will continue your researches?
如果您希望这样 福尔摩斯先生
If you say so, Mr. Holmes.
我希望这样
I do say so.
并且盯住一位默多克 格尔的住所
And keep your eye on the premises of a certain Murdoch Gull.
什么？你认为是默多克？
Yes? Murdoch, you think?
他是一切离经叛道的维护者 他可能是我们要找的人
Is the fence for anything out of the ordinary? It could be a man.
还有一件事 福尔摩斯先生
One more thing, Mr. Holmes, sir.
我们将万分荣幸
The men and I would be very honoured
如果圣诞节您愿意来访
if you'd drop by Christmas Eve.
我们将在圣诞节举办一个晚会
We try to get a bit festive at Christmas, and
邀请一些客人
we like to invite a few guests.
圣诞节
Christmas...
玛丽
Mary?
好了 这才刚开始
There. It's a start.
哈德森太太
Mrs. Hudson.
福尔摩斯先生？
Mr. Holmes?
我该再送华生什么礼物好呢
How am I supposed to think up yet another present for Watson?
每年这时你都让我头痛
I mean, every year you inflict this agony on me.
很简单 福尔摩斯先生 去家美家吧
It's quite simple, Mr. Holmes. You go to Gamages.
家美家
Gamages?
是的 在霍尔 是家百货商店
Yes. It's in Holborn, a department store.
百姓商场 你会眼花缭乱的
The people's Emporium. You will be quite spoilt for ideas.
哈德森太太 你怎么敢拿走我的一叶兰
Mrs. Hudson, how dare you take my aspidistra?
我就是敢
I do dare.
下午好 库欣小姐 节日愉快
Afternoon, Miss Cushing. Season's Greetings, eh?
下午好 威尔金森
Good afternoon, Wilkinson.
看起来马上又要下雪
Looks like we're in for a bit more snow before long.
我真希望别下
I do hope not.
这是怎么回事 贾科泰先生
What is this Monsieur Jacotett?
啊 苏珊女士
Ah, Madame Suzan.
我们已经说好
Our arrangement is
你可以在晚饭后坐在客厅火炉旁
that you may sit by the parlour fire after dinner.
否则 我将非常感激
Otherwise, I would be obliged,
如果您在这房子里时 只呆在自己房间里
when you are in the house, if you would keep to your room.
你妹妹莎拉 是她允许我的 女士
Your sister, Sarah, gave me permission, Madame.
这是我家 不是我妹妹的
This is my house, not my sister's.
就算她这么说了 当然我很怀疑
Even if she said it, which I doubt.
如果我妹妹允许
I would be most surprised if my sister gave
我的房客使用厨房
the run of the kitchen to my lodger.
你会惊讶令妹给了我什么
You would be surprised what your sister gives.
非常惊讶
Very surprised.
如果您现在能离开厨房 我将十分感激 先生
I think I would be obliged if you left the kitchen now, Monsieur.
我觉得您没听到我在说什么
I don't think you hear what I am saying.
苏珊
Susan.
马塞尔...
Marcel...
噢 苏珊 成功了 他们让我当旅店的看守人
Oh Susan, it has worked. They have made me warden at the mission.
现在你问问她 她给了我什么
Now you ask her what she gave me.
是你给了贾科泰先生
Did you give Monsieur Jacotett
随意使用厨房的准许吗
permission to help himself in here, in the kitchen?
我给过一次 我没想到他会...
I believe I did, once. I didn't realize he'd...
问她
Ask her.
你是什么意思 到底怎么回事
What do you mean? What is going on?
问她
Ask her.
你们英国人真是伪善
You English are such hypocrites.
你现在告诉她你给了我什么
Now you tell her what you gave me.
什么？
What?
这是怎么回事？
What is all this about?
谁能告诉我到底怎么...
Will someone please tell me what's going?
我懂了
I see.
我懂了 很好
I see. Very well.
你现在是看守人了 到那儿住去吧
You are warden now. Go and live there then.
你在旅店会有住处的 去那儿
You'll have quarters at the mission. Go there.
我不想你留在我家 走
I don't want you under my roof. Go.
我不会让你住在这儿 不会
I won't have you here, I won't.
而你 先生 你立刻离开我家
And as for you Monsieur, you will leave my house immediately.
立刻 不然我就叫警察
Immediately. Or I will call the police.
你的行李将被打包后
Your belongings will be packed and
留在旁门那
left at the tradesmen's entrance for your collection.
你怎么敢
How dare you!
你简直和妈妈一模一样
You sound exactly like mother.
那又如何
What if I do?
我还以为她过世后 自己再也不会 听到那样的话
I thought I'd heard the last of that sort of thing when she died.
你怎敢如此说妈妈
How dare you talk about mother like that!
我像她有什么不好吗？
It's just as well I am like her.
不然我不知道我们家会发生什么
I don't know what would happen to this family otherwise.
你把我们都绑在你身边
Oh you hold us all together do you?
你真伟大
How splendid you are!
你发现玛丽不声不响 就离开了吗
Do you realize that Mary has gone away without telling anyone?
好极了 她最终还是表现出了点勇气
Good. She's showing some spirit at last.
你说这好极了？
You call that good?
有时候我觉得你不仅一事无成
Sometimes you're not just feckless,
而且故意推卸责任
I think you're deliberately irresponsible.
玛丽已经结婚了
Mary is a married woman.
不是你的功劳 你到最后都反对他们
Well, no thanks to you. You stood in her way to the last.
吉姆 布劳纳永远也不够资格 成为我们家一员 是吗？
Jim Browner was never good enough for our family, was he?
库欣少校的女儿们
The daughters of Major Cushing RE?
无所谓 他是个赌棍 我们的父亲则是...
Never mind, he was a gambling wastrel. Our father was...
住口 如果有谁让我们家蒙羞...
Be quiet. If anyone has disgraced this family...
那就是我？
It's me?
我警告你 总有一天这些责任
I warn you, one day this diet of respectability
会让你自食其果
is going to make you ill.
你糟透了
You are so... horrid.
亲爱的哈德森太太
Ah dear Mrs. Hudson.
福尔摩斯先生 有个人和医生一起来了
Mr. Holmes, the doctor has someone with him.
苏珊 库欣小姐
A Miss Susan Cushing.
知道了 请您拿好这个
Oh well. You'd better hold onto this.
这是什么
This is...
那是什么
What's that?
是棵圣诞树
Ah, that is a Christmas tree,
一棵挪威云杉
it's a Norway spruce.
这位是库欣小姐
This is Miss Cushing.
库欣小姐很担心她的妹妹布劳纳太太
Miss Cushing is concerned about her sister, Mrs. Browner.
请继续
Pray continue.
库欣小姐最小的妹妹
Miss Cushing's youngest sister,
和她住得并不远 就在东坎伯威尔
lives not far from her, just east of Camberwell.
布劳纳太太每周五都来她家喝茶
Mrs. Browner visits her every Friday for tea,
除非她通知了不来 而这也很少发生
unless she sends excuses, which is most unusual.
上个星期五 19号
Last Friday, the nineteenth,
布劳纳太太既未送来消息亦未到来
Mrs. Browner failed to send excuses or to arrive.
于是库欣小姐询问了她的房客
So, Miss Cushing has made inquiries at her lodgings,
但是布劳纳太太打上个礼拜四起 就不曾露面
but Mrs. Browner has not been seen there since last Thursday.
听起来像是她失踪了
Sounds to me as if she has disappeared.
很显然 福尔摩斯
Evidently, Holmes.
她的失踪可能有一两个原因
There could be one or two reasons for her disappearance.
要不就是有别的什么人希望她失踪
or because somebody else wished her to disappear.
你知道有什么原因 可能使别人想让她消失吗？
Do you know of any reason why anyone should want her to disappear?
玛丽？没有
Mary? None.
她是最可爱的人 人人都喜欢她
She's the most loveable of creatures. Everyone loves her.
至于她的下落
As to her whereabouts,
我建议 您试试失踪人口处
I mean, I suggest that you try the missing people agency.
我给您一张地址清单
I could find you a list of addresses.
好了 哈
There, hah.
真迷人 不是吗
Charming, isn't it?
对那棵云杉的小小改进
Slight improvement on that rather sad pices excelsa.
莎拉
Sarah.
马塞尔
Marcel.
我等不了了 你让我疯狂 莎拉
The waiting possessed me. You drive me mad Sarah.
有时候我觉得我被附身了
Sometimes I think I'm possessed.
你现在住哪？
Where are you now?
医院附近的一个狗窝
Some filthy hole near the hospital.
都因为你姐姐 我不会让她忘记此事的
Thanks to your sister. I will not let her forget this.
圣诞节你要去比利时吗
Are you going to Belgium still for Christmas?
是的 我叔叔住在奥斯坦德附近
Yes. My uncle in Ostend.
你回来后 我会为你写一封介绍信
Well, when you come back, I'll write a reference for you.
我现在是此处的看守 它能算数
I'm Warden of this place. It'll count.
我爱你
I love you.
圣诞节以后来找我
Come to me after Christmas.
是邮件 库欣小姐
The post, Miss Cushing.
我把包裹放在树下好吗
Shall I put the parcels under the tree?
好的
Yes, please.
还是没有布劳纳太太的消息？
Nothing from Mrs. Browner, yet?
还是没有
Nothing as yet, no.
撒津店今天送的东西里有马迪拉酒吗？
Did Sudgen's include the Madeira in their delivery today?
是的 库欣小姐 今晚的一切都准备好了
Yes, Miss Cushing. Everything's ready for this evening.
谢谢
Thank you.
节日快乐 布拉德布鲁克先生
Compliments of the season, Mr. Bradbrook.
非常感谢 您也是
Thank you very much, and the very same to you.
库欣小姐 我说库欣小姐
Miss Cushing. I say Miss Cushing.
抱歉
Sorry.
布拉德布鲁克先生
Mr. Bradbrook.
敢问您的妹妹 莎拉会来是吗
I dare say your sister, Sarah, will be joining us?
很遗憾她不来 布拉德布鲁克先生
I'm afraid not, Mr. Bradbrook.
她现在是米申旅店的看守人
She's Warden now of the Mission Hostel now
她有责任为了旅客留在那里
her duties to her residents will keep her there.
恐怕我只能 在周日见到她了
I shall see her only on Sundays now I fear.
很遗憾让您失望了 布拉德布鲁克先生
I'm sorry to disappoint you, Mr. Bradbrook.
噢 不不不 您没有 一点也没
No, no, no you haven't, not at all.
来吧 布拉德布鲁克先生 今天是平安夜
Come now, Mr. Bradbrook. It is Christmas Eve.
为了补偿您 我们晚饭一结束就来拆圣诞树下的礼物
To make up, we shall open our presents from the tree
而不必等到午夜
straight after supper instead of at midnight.
您说呢？
What do you say?
很好 很好 太棒了 就这么做
Very well. Yes. Yes, fine. Splendid. Let's do that.
格拉德斯通最后会很开心的
Well, Gladstone will be pleased at least.
其中有一份是给它的礼物
There is a treat somewhere for him.
欢迎 先生们 真高兴你们能来
Welcome gentlemen, very good of you to come.
格尔 逮着他了？
Gull? Has he been arrested?
没有 福尔摩斯先生
No, Mr. Holmes.
他是来投诉的
He's come to complain.
是吗？
Has he indeed?
他发现了我们在监视他 他不喜欢
He has spotted our surveillance of him. He doesn't like it.
你不会放弃？
You won't give up?
当然不会
Dear me, no.
好好玩吧
Join the party.
快点
Come on.
请进
Yes. Come in.
噢 我亲爱的朋友 你穿上它了
Oh, my dear fellow, you are wearing it.
我得试试 它最大的好处
Well, I had to try it. What's so good about it is...
就是可以在车笼头前铺开 如果你需要的话
it stretches forward over the handlebars if you need it.
你到底在哪儿发现的？
Where on earth did you find it?
家美家 百姓商场
Gamages, the people's Emporium.
谢谢 太棒了
Thank you. Pipe. Magnificent.
霍金斯 请进来吧 亲爱的朋友 请坐
Hawkins, do come in, dear fellow. Please, sit down.
盗墓贼又有什么新消息？
What is the news of the grave robberies?
坎伯威尔分局来了消息
The Camberwell force have been on to me.
那儿发生了一件意外 他们怀疑两件事是否有关系
An incident down there. They were wondering if it had any connection.
我个人并不认为有 但我需要您的意见 福尔摩斯先生
I don't think it does myself, but I'd value your opinion Mr. Holmes.
我们需要把这个下流的小玩笑 解决了处理掉
We need to get this nasty little joke solved and out of the way.
玩笑？
Joke?
一位尊敬的女士 在平安夜和朋友们一起 拆开她的包裹
Respectable lady, in company opening her parcels, Christmas Eve.
其中一件有点奇怪 装满了盐 她把盐倒光
One of them's bit odd, full of salt. She empties out the salt.
里面是什么？
What's in it?
两只刚切下来的人耳
Two freshly severed human ears.
我们认为是个医学院学生干的
We think it was a medical student.
她曾有个房客是医学院学生
She had a medical student as a lodger.
解剖系学生可以
Post-mortem anatomy can make
轻而易举的做到
certain individuals thoroughly callous.
她在圣诞节前把他赶出来 显然有些争吵
She threw him out just before Christmas. Bit of a row. Apparently.
无论如何 因为我知道您的办案方法 福尔摩斯先生
Anyway, knowing your methods, Mr. Holmes,
我把耳朵原封不动 留在那位女士的家里
I've had the ears left quite untouched at the lady's house.
就在
Which is,
特拉法尔加别墅 坎波维尔 一位苏珊 库欣小姐
yes. Here it is. Trafalgar Villa, Camberwell, A Miss Susan Cushing.
福尔摩斯先生 您终于来帮我找玛丽了吗
Oh, Mr. Holmes, have you come to help me find Mary after all?
我很抱歉 库欣小姐
I'm afraid not, Miss Cushing.
警督请我来 查另一单不幸的案件
The Inspector has asked me to look into that other, unfortunate business.
噢 那个 霍金斯先生 我不会把东西放在这里
Oh, that. Well, I won't have those things in the house, Mr. Hawkins.
如果您想看看的话
If you wish to see them,
您得去温室
you must go to the conservatory.
那个不幸的年轻人被逮住了没
Have you arrested that wretched young man yet?
只是时间问题 库欣小姐
Just a matter of time, Miss Cushing.
哈里奇的邮戳
Postmarked Harwich.
贾科泰这个学生现在
Now this student fellow Jacotett
在回家过圣诞节
was going home for Christmas
从哈里奇去往奥斯坦德
to Ostend via Harwich.
是的 我同意
Yes, I agree,
哈里奇能说明这点 字迹很差
Harwich is persuasive. The writing is poor.
未受过教育
Uneducated.
我知道医疗行业的人 字迹都很潦草
I know the medical profession is notorious for its illegibility,
但是这个 用粗头钢笔写的
but this, written with a broad nibbed pen,
墨水很差
very inferior ink.
涂过柏油的麻绳
Tarred twine.
斯德哥尔摩柏油
Stockholm tar.
结绳原封未动
Knots intact.
粗盐
Rough salt...
埋在里面的是…
and embedded in it...
这些特殊的东西
These very singular enclosures.
你怎么看 华生
What do you think of it, Watson?
这个耳朵穿过耳洞
A ring has been torn from this ear.
不是一对
They are not a pair.
贾科泰从解剖室 很容易挑两只
I suppose it would be rather easier for Jacotett to have abstracted ears
不成对的耳朵
from a dissecting room which were not actually a pair.
为什么？
To what purpose?
某种恶作剧
Some kind of disgusting practical joke.
这不是恶作剧
Gentlemen, this is no practical joke.
当你进入解剖室里 首先察觉到的是什么？
What first strikes you when you enter a dissecting room?
甲醛
Formaldehyde.
该死 应该能问到甲醛味
Dammit, it should smell of formaldehyde.
但是这个没有 这不是恶作剧
And it does not. This is no practical joke.
这是严重的犯罪
This is a serious crime.
你妹妹 库欣小姐
Your sister, Miss Cushing.
玛丽 终于来了
Mary. At last,
"玛丽 玛丽 十分叛逆"
Mary, Mary, quite contrary.
我以为是玛丽
I thought it was Mary.
我来拿我的东西
I've come to take some more of my things.
我们吵架之前我给你买了个礼物
I bought you a present before we argued.
你还是收下吧
You may as well have it.
我不想要 我不想要
I don't want it. I don't want it.
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?
又是什么恶心的玩笑吗
Is it another disgusting prank?
什么
What?
毕竟他是你的朋友
Well, he was your friend, after all.
谁
Who was?
我不想要你的恐怖包裹
I don't want your horrid parcel.
拿去 保留一点礼仪吧 姐姐
Take it. Let's preserve the proprieties at least, sister.
礼仪？
Proprieties?
你敢谈礼仪？
You dare to talk about the proprieties?
你一生都在破坏社会规范
You have flouted the rules of society all your life.
而你还敢厚颜无耻的指责我
And you had the effrontery to accuse me
阻止玛丽嫁给那个男人
of interfering with Mary's marrying that man?
难道不是？
Didn't you?
但是你干了什么
But what did you do?
我干了什么 我什么也没干
What did I do? I did nothing.
你心知肚明 你给玛丽介绍了别的男人
You know what you did. You introduced Mary to other men.
带坏她 玛丽告诉了我她的无辜
Corrupting her. Mary has told me in her innocence.
她责怪我？
She accused me?
玛丽从不责怪任何人 你知道
Mary accuses no one. You know that.
但我知道你给她带来了不幸
But I see your hand in her unhappiness.
胡说
Nonsense.
为什么吉姆 布劳纳又开始酗酒
Why did Jim Browner start drinking again?
他对玛丽发过誓 因此他们在才一起的
He signed the pledge for Mary. That's what brought them together.
她把蓝色丝带别在他胸前 他已经重新做人了
She pinned the blue ribbon to his chest and he was a new man.
为什么他打破他的誓言？
So why did he break his pledge?
为什么问我？
Why ask me?
你为什么和他吵架
Why did you quarrel with him?
我从来不赞成吉姆 布劳纳 这是事实
I never approved of Jim Browner, that's true, but he deserved-
但他不应该因为你的多事 而重新酗酒
better than being driven back to drink by your meddling.
我回来了
I'm back.
吉姆
Jim.
你好 莎拉
Hello Sarah.
玛丽没想到你会这么早回来
Mary wasn't expecting you till much later.
我赶上了尾潮 节约了一次潮汐的时间
I managed to catch the tail end of the flood. Saved a whole tide.
她不在家？
She not here then?
不 库珀老奶奶又不舒服了 玛丽在陪她
No. Old Mrs. Cooper's not well again. Mary's with her.
我说我会来帮她洗衣服 她马上就回来
I said I'd help her with the laundry. She'll be back soon.
你帮了她很多 不是吗
You help her a lot, don't you?
真好
That's nice.
我猜你知道我为什么帮她？
You know why I help her I suppose?
什么
What?
为什么我老在这儿
Why I'm always round here.
你是她姐姐
You're her sister.
她不在身边五分钟 你都会不高兴 是吗 吉姆？
Can't you be happy for five minutes without her, Jim?
来 帮帮忙
Here, make yourself useful.
然后放下这一边
Drop the side then.
什么？
What?
你放下这个 然后拿起另一边
Well you drop this and bring it up the other side.
你什么意思 玛丽不这么做
What do you mean? Mary doesn't do that.
我敢说 玛丽不做的事情多着呢
There are plenty of things Mary doesn't do, I dare say.
我来教你怎么做
Look, I'll show you how to do it, shall I?
现在
Now...
过来 你拿着这个角
Now, come on. You take this corner.
好 现在 你放下这个
Right now, you drop this,
然后你拿起这个 另一边
and you bring it up the other side.
你自己来 这不是我做的 我可不要
You do it yourself. That's not for me. I want no part of that.
把女人的工作塞给我 你自己去做吧
Pushing women's work at me. You keep that to yourself.
福尔摩斯先生和另一位先生来看你 夫人
Mr. Holmes and the other gentlemen to see you, madam.
让他们别把那些东西带进来
As long as they don't bring those things near me.
他现在在哪
And where is he now?
布劳纳和玛丽结婚时
Mr. Browner was on the South American line
在跑南美航线 但他太爱她了
when he and Mary married. But he was so fond of her,
于是他转到 北海航船上
that he found himself a berth in the North Sea boats.
跑伦敦-登荷德航线
The London-Den Helder line.
玛丽爱他吗
And is Mary fond of him?
他们是恋爱结婚
It was a love match.
恋爱？
Love?
尽管…
Although...
什么？
Yes?
当时我不愿意承认这个事实
I was loath to acknowledge it at the time.
为什么
Why was that?
我觉得我的姐妹 不该嫁给一个船员
I didn't think a sister of mine should be marrying a steward.
现在呢 您现在感觉如何
And now? How do you feel now?
我想吉姆和玛丽本可以幸福
I think Jim and Mary could be happy.
您的意思是他们并不幸福？
You mean they weren't?
一开始是的
They were at first.
然后呢
What happened?
也许你该问问莎拉
Perhaps you should ask Sarah.
她在那里住过一阵子
She practically lived there for a while.
现在布劳纳先生在哪条船上？
Which ship is Mr. Browner serving with at present?
"五朔节"号
The "May Morning".
17号启程 开往比利时和荷兰
She sailed on the seventeenth for Belgium and Holland.
圣诞节他们在鹿特丹
They were in Rotterdam over Christmas.
船员抽签 吉姆今年运气不好
The crews draw lots and Jim was unlucky this year.
玛丽得和我和莎拉一起过圣诞节
Mary was to have spent Christmas with Sarah and me.
而现在莎拉 在旅店做看守人
And now Sarah, of course, is now Warden at the mission.
您是否不让她和您住一起？
Are you sad not to have her living with you still?
是的
Yes I am.
实话告诉你吧 福尔摩斯先生
Well to tell you the truth, Mr. Holmes,
我们俩相处得不好
things are not well between us.
你们吵架了？为了什么？
You have quarreled? What about?
也许会和你妹妹 玛丽的失踪有关系
It may have a bearing on what has happened to your sister, Mary.
我知道 当然有关 你以为我不知道吗
I know that. Of course it does. Do you think I don't know that?
我认为一切都是她的错
I blame her for everything.
莎拉？
Sarah?
当然 莎拉
Of course. Sarah.
她老呆在玛丽家 完全没有这个必要
She spent far more time than was necessary at Mary's lodgings.
吉姆和玛丽才新婚
Jim and Mary were just married,
过着自己的新生活 结交新朋友
making their own life, making their own friends.
而莎拉给他们介绍了亚历克 费尔贝恩
Then Sarah introduced Alec Fairbairn to them.
我知道这不是好意
I know it was not generously done.
看起来莎拉是想羞辱吉姆 布劳纳
Sarah seemed to want to shame Jim Browner.
我不知道吉姆对莎拉做了什么
I don't know what Jim had done to Sarah,
但好像她恨他 我相信…
but she seemed to hate him. I believe that...
你相信什么
You believe what?
问她
Ask her.
问莎拉 她在这里收拾她的东西
Ask Sarah. She is here in the house collecting her things.
问她是不是想让玛丽和亚历克 费尔贝恩私奔
Ask her if she did not mean Mary to go off with Alec Fairbairn.
这就是她的目的
That's what she wanted.
我知道
I know it.
她已经收到消息了
Ah, the message has been received then.
咖啡？先生
Cafe, Monsieur.
谢谢你的帮助 警督
Thank you for your help, Inspector.
这很难 福尔摩斯先生 我们不能忽视证据
It's very difficult, Mr. Holmes. We can't ignore the evidence.
我们知道了什么？包裹里的两只耳朵
What've we got? Two severed ears in a parcel.
我们知道一个医学院学生贾科泰
We've got the medical student,
他被赶出了这位女士的家
Jacotett who's been thrown out of the lady's house.
强烈的动机 包裹是19号从哈里奇寄出的
Strong motive. Parcel postmarked Harwich on the nineteenth.
他19号也在哈里奇 只有这么多了
He was in Harwich on the nineteenth. That's as good as you get.
你的推理很浅显易懂 霍金斯
Your logic seems foolproof Hawkins.
谢谢
Thank you. Well... Yes.
遗憾的是我不能阻止此事登报
I just regret that I haven't been able to keep it out of the newspapers.
他们正在为明早的头版写这个报道
They're running the story in tomorrow morning's first editions.
他们也得到了苏珊 库欣小姐的名字
They've also managed to get hold of Miss Susan Cushing's name.
她不会喜欢这样的
She won't like that.
可怜的女人
No. Poor woman.
那么另一件案子 福尔摩斯先生
This other matter then, Mr. Holmes.
你也有想法了 是吧？
You've clearly got some thoughts on that, haven't you?
我相信 某位华生医生的同行
It's my belief, that a member of Dr. Watson's profession,
为了某种目的铤而走险
possibly of some distinction, has overstepped the mark.
所有尸体都是拳击手的 业余或者其他的
The corpses all belong to pugilists, amateur or otherwise.
搏斗太久的拳击手
What is the unfortunate characteristic
有什么不幸的特征？
of boxers who have fought too long?
他们的脑部会留下很多创伤
Well, there can be such scarring of the brain
会像喝醉了酒似的 说话含糊
that the men behave as if drunk, slurred speech,
记忆缺失或者其他 他们变得头昏眼花
loss of memory and so on. They become punch drunk.
正是如此
Precisely.
您是说有人在研究 脑部组织病理学？
You mean somebody is studying the pathology of brain tissues?
我认为正是如此
For all the best reasons, I dare say.
他们研究的热情 超过了他们的理性
And their passion of the subject has outrun their judgment.
马库斯 兰宁爵士 我赌一个月的工资是马库斯爵士
Sir Marcus Lanyon, I'll wager a month's salary on Sir Marcus.
这正是他的专业
That is precisely his specialty
他没有耐心 冷血无情
and he is impatient to a fault, ruthlessly impatient.
现在你知道了 警督
There you have it, Inspector.
她很沮丧
She is very down.
下午她回来以后 就一直这样
Like this ever since she got back here this afternoon.
库欣小姐？
Miss Cushing.
你和你的妹夫布劳纳先生 为何事争吵？
Why did you quarrel with your brother-in-law, Mr. Browner?
什么？你是谁 为何在此
What? Who are you, what are you doing here?
这位是歇洛克 福尔摩斯
This is Sherlock Holmes,
他正在调查你的妹妹 玛丽的失踪案
he is investigating the disappearance of your sister, Mary.
她和亚历克 费尔贝恩跑了 就是这样
She's gone off with Alec Fairbairn, that's all.
为什么？
Why?
她被她丈夫吓坏了
She had become frightened of her husband.
为什么
Why?
吉姆 布劳纳是个酒鬼
Jim Browner was a drunkard.
他打她 为人卑劣
He offered her violence. He was beneath contempt.
你对这对耳朵作何解释 库欣小姐
What is your explanation for the severed ears, Miss Cushing?
你见过那个硬纸盒子了 在你姐姐家
You saw the cardboard box. At your sister's house.
那对耳朵是给你的 不是吗
Those severed ears were meant for you were they not?
这个信息是给你的 你知道它们意味着什么
The message was for you. You understood what they meant.
是马塞尔 贾科泰寄来的
Marcel Jacotett sent them.
他告诉我他会做些什么
He told me he might do something.
我没想到他会做这么恶心的事儿
I didn't realize he would do anything so disgusting.
她在说谎 华生
She is lying, Watson.
她在空口说白话
She's lying through her teeth.
格尔在外面
Gull is outside.
太棒了
ExceHenL
我去过航线办公室了
I've been to the shipping line offices too.
然后？
And?
正如你所认为
It's as you thought. The "May Morning"
"五朔节"号于17号从伦敦出发驶往登荷德
set sail from London for Den Helder on the seventeenth,
但是一个大桶松开了
but a hogshead got loose in her hold.
使一个横梁脱了节 必须进港维修
She sprang a plate and had to put in for repairs.
在哈里奇？
To Harwich?
在哈里奇 船员18号放假
To Harwich. The crew were given leave on the eighteenth.
"五朔月"号在19号晚启程
The "May Morning" left late on the nineteenth,
就是包裹寄出的同一天
the day the parcel was posted.
太棒了 华生 有答案了
Excellent Watson. We have it.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
格尔先生
Mr. Gull.
他们来了电报 吉姆 布劳纳今晚7点
They have telegraphed. Jim Browner came off the ferry at Ramsgate at
在拉姆斯盖特下船
seven o'clock this evening.
很好 我就知道我可以信任您
Good. I knew I could rely on you.
我可以信任您吗
And I can rely on you, can I?
你能
You can.
马库斯 兰宁爵士这个名字 对你有什么意义吗？
Does the name Sir Marcus Lanyon mean anything to you?
可能有
It might.
他会得到警告
He will be warned off.
您从中获利的工作将结束
The orders from which you have been profiting will dry up
同样警察对您的兴趣也会随之消失
but so will the police interest in you.
我很满意这个结果
I'll be satisfied with that.
我们谈了笔好买卖 格尔先生
We've acquired a bargain, Mr. Gull.
福尔摩斯？
Holmes.
等等
Hold on.
包裹上的绳结 是单套结和接绳结
The knots used on the parcel were a bowline and a sheet bend.
是的 水手结
Yes, sailor's knots.
你知道水手们一般不会磨刀
You know that sailors deliberately do not sharpen their knives?
是的 除非有事故
Ah, in case of accidents.
因此这个残忍的切割
Hence the crude amputations.
哈里奇是关键 而布劳纳当时在那儿
Harwich was the key and Browner was there.
现在我推测
Now, I suppose...
布劳纳意外回到家中
Browner, returned unexpectedly,
发现他妻子和费尔贝恩在一起
found his wife with Fairbairn.
他尾随他们 杀害了他们
He followed them. He murdered them both.
各切下他们一人的耳朵
He severed an ear from each
然后寄给莎拉 库欣
and sent them as he thought to Sarah Cushing.
当然他会立刻到那里
Of course, he will go there immediately.
他等不及要告诉她
He will be desperate
那两只耳朵是给她的 而非给她姐姐
for her to know that the severed ears were for her, not for her sister.
就是这样
Well, that being the case...
现在周日也有火车
The railway is operating as if it were a Sunday.
为什么
Why?
因为还是圣诞期间
Because the Christmas holiday is still on.
你有没有意识到布劳纳 可能搭更早的火车？
Do you realize, Browner could have caught a much earlier train.
不 我没有
No, I did not know.
玛丽
Mary.
这是什么 福尔摩斯先生
What is this, Mr. Holmes?
一次你的特殊经历 警督
A unique experience for you, Inspector.
你或许能在知道一桩谋杀发生之前
You may apprehend a murderer
就抓到一个凶杀
before you have even acknowledged there has been a murder.
是的 你惊讶吧
Aye. Well you may stare.
看着我 莎拉 库欣 这是你的拿手好戏
Look at me Sarah Cushing, this is your handiwork.
你做了什么 吉姆？
What have you done, Jim?
我做了什么？
What have I done?
是你做了什么
Nay, it's what you've done.
我求求你 好好看着我
I beg you, Jim. Look on me kindly.
我做的一切 都是为了你
Whatever I did, I did for you.
是你
It was you.
是你毒害了她的思想
You poisoned her mind.
我这么做是为了你
I did it for you.
他们抓住了那个房客 我告诉他们是他做的
They have arrested the lodger. I told them he did it.
他们丝毫没有怀疑你 吉姆 你可以逃脱
They suspect nothing of you, Jim. You can get away.
逃脱？你以为我能逃脱
Get away? You think I can get away?
当一切没发生过 你这么以为 不是吗 你疯了
Put it all behind me, do you think? Do you? Well, you're mad.
是我 就在这儿
It is me. It's in here.
每一幕每一幕
Every last moment of it.
每天都在我面前 不断重现
Comes out of the daylight at me. Goes on and on.
自打犯案起 我不敢闭着眼睛睡觉
I tell you, I dare not shut an eye and sleep since I did it.
我不敢一个人呆着
I'm never without one or the other before me.
愿你的血在你的血管里腐败
May the blood rot in your veins, Sarah Cushing.
不 不
No, no.
我爱你 我爱你
I love you. I love you.
我相信 我告诉你
I believe you do. I tell you something,
我宁愿从被我杀死的她口中听到一个字 也不要你的爱
I'd rather have one kind word from her I've killed than all your love.
我宁愿看着她多呼吸一分钟
I'd rather see her breathing one minute
也不要你给我一辈子
more than a lifetime that you could give me.
别这么说 别这么说
Don't say that. Don't say that. Don't say that.
她爱我
She loved me,
这就是一切的根源
that the rule of the business.
但是她知道
But she knew,
她知道 她知道我
she knew, she knew I,
我想到我泥地里的脚印
I thought more of my wife's footprint in the mud
多于想到她的身体和灵魂
than I did of her, body and soul.
做梦也没想到啊
Whoever would have dreamt it?
而且
And,
在拒绝了莎拉的殷勤之后
after you'd rejected Sarah's advances?
我一个字也没对玛丽说 我想这会让她难过
I never said a word to Mary for I thought it would grieve her.
然后我发现玛丽开始变了
Then I began to see a change in Mary herself.
我妻子一向 善解人意
My wife had always been so understanding.
现在她对一切都怀疑
Now she was suspicious of everything I did.
我们开始无谓的争吵 完全没有原因
We began to row about nothing, nothing at all.
这让我发狂
And it maddened me.
事实也是如此吗？
And this was said as well?
是的 不是我瞎想
Aye, I didn't see it then mind.
我只是看到一切都不对了
I just saw it all go wrong.
她和玛丽形影不离
She and Mary were inseparable and then,
后来我开了戒
well then I broke my blue ribbon
又开始酗酒
and began drinking again.
所以玛丽有理由讨厌我了
So Mary had some reason to be disgusted with me now.
然后这个费尔贝恩就插进来了
And then this Fairbairn fellow chipped in.
他是个时髦浮华的小伙子
He was a dashing, swaggering sort of a chap.
聪明 长着一头卷发 还受过教育 我认为他很健谈
Smart and curled, educated too, I reckon he could talk, he could.
是一件小事
Blind I was.
使我产生了疑虑
It was a little thing put me on to him.
我那天偶尔来到客厅 一进门
I came into the parlor unexpected one day and as I came in
我看见我妻子眼睛里闪过欢迎的光
I saw the light of welcome in my wife's eyes, but
但当她发现是我时
when she saw it was me,
她带着失望的表情转身就走了
she turned away with a look of disappointment.
肯定是把我当成亚历克 费尔贝恩了 不会是别人
There was no one but Alec Fairbairn whose steps she could mistake for mine.
从那一刻起我的平静就一去不复返了
I tell you, from that moment on my peace was gone.
莎拉当时在厨房 我直接走进厨房 告诉她
Sarah was in the kitchen and I went straight through and I told her that
如果费尔贝恩再出现在我家
"if Fairbairn ever set foot in my place again"
我就把他的耳朵留给你做纪念
"I'd send her his ears for a keepsake".
我希望你是在法国犯下这个案子
I believe I could wish you had committed this deed of yours in France.
他们承认冲动犯罪
They acknowledge the crime of passion there.
你不会让他们把我单独留在这 是吗 先生
You won't let them leave me alone, will you sir?
不
No.
我不会
I won't.
我走的时候会叫个警官进来
When I leave I'll send an officer in.
我不想一个人
I don't like to be alone, see.
到你了
Your turn.
我去去就来
Won't be a minute.
她让事情变糟的 是吗
She made it go wrong, didn't she?
你心里从来都只有我
And you never thought of anyone but me.
是吗 吉姆？
Did you, Jim?
她爱你 她让我恨你
She loved you and she made me hate you.
看起来似乎她有什么秘密
There. It was if you had a secret, you see.
她让我往最坏处想
She made me think the worst.
这个秘密就是她爱我？
The secret was her love with me?
你该让她远离我们的生活 吉姆
You should have got rid of her from our lives, Jim.
我知道 我知道那会伤害你
I know. But I thought it would hurt you.
看看我们现在
Look at us now.
我真傻 真是瞎了眼
I was stupid. Blind as a pickle.
这是什么意思 华生
What is the meaning of it, Watson?
这一连串的痛苦
What is the object of
暴力和恐惧究竟是为了什么？
this circle of misery and violence and fear?
一定有某种目的
It must have a purpose
不然我们这个宇宙就毫无意义
or our universe had no meaning
而这是无法想象的 但是是什么目的呢？
and that is unthinkable, but what purpose?
这是人类的大问题
That is humanity's great problem
思索了多少年 也没有答案
for which reason so far has no answer.